Contact

daniel@basegeo.com

www.linkedin.com/in/danielberstein (LinkedIn)

daniel.berste.in/ (Personal) daniel.berste.in/blog/ (Blog) slashdot.org/~dberstein (Other)

Top Skills

Terraform

Grafana

Loki

Languages

Spanish (Native or Bilingual) English (Native or Bilingual) Hebrew (Limited Working)

Daniel Berstein

Versatile techie

Israel

Summary

Expert PHP developer, passionate for new technologies and challenges.

Specialties: Zend Certified Engineer for PHP 4 and 5. Development of distributed GIS systems, expert in SQL and PL/SQL, knowledgeable in Oracle, Microsoft SqlServer, MySQL and Firebird, expert PHP developer.

Experience

Cycode

DevOps Engineer

January 2022 - June 2022 (6 months)

Kubernetes monitoring/alerting stack researcher:

- Grafana dashboards, both static & dynamically generated, with configurable Slack notifications from mixed datasources: Mimir/Prometheus/Loki+Promtail with configurable variety of authentication methods
- Provisioned via Terraform module(s) to GKE/EKS/custom clusters, automated by Gitlab CI/CD pipeline(s)

BlazeMeter

4 years 9 months

Staff Software Engineer

January 2020 - October 2021 (1 year 10 months)

CA Technologies | Broadcom

- Mentoring new engineers about platform
- Non-trivial tasks lead (ie. minimize breaking changes for some new features)

Sr Software Engineer

February 2017 - January 2020 (3 years)

CA Technologies | Broadcom

Performance rocker, sprint surfer

- Multi-cloud solutions: GCP, AWS, Azure: SDK client in PHP 5-7 and Python 2-3 for:

- Provisioning of VMs
- S3-compatible solution: ie. Minio and boto3
- etc.
- Convert Docker image solution to native multi-platform solution using PyInstaller and NSSM for Win32 service management
- Introduced use of Alpine Linux for reduced security footprint and size/cost improvements
- Splunk dashboards

ironSource

3 years

Senior back-end solutions developer July 2014 - October 2016 (2 years 4 months)

Implemented strategic, tactic and operational solutions using a variety of technologies; maintainer of legacy code-base. Keeper of high traffic web properties with multi-million hits a day retaining high performance, security and appraisal.

C# Developer

November 2013 - June 2014 (8 months)

Building C# solutions for our digital display platform on Azure.

AfterDownload Ltd

Senior developer

October 2011 - December 2013 (2 years 3 months)

Reporting directly to the CTO and the Director of R&D.

Teleweb Services

3 years 2 months

R&D Special Operations Senior Developer September 2010 - September 2011 (1 year 1 month) Tel Aviv

R&D Team Leader

May 2009 - September 2010 (1 year 5 months)

Senior PHP Developer

August 2008 - December 2009 (1 year 5 months)

Zend by Perforce PHP Developer

May 2006 - July 2008 (2 years 3 months)

Maintainer of mission critical, fault tolerant web systems. Part of geographically distributed team (US east/west, Germany, Israel).

Koret

Senior PHP Developer November 2005 - May 2006 (7 months)

dmapas.com
Software Engineer Proyect Leader
July 2001 - May 2005 (3 years 11 months)
Leader of software development team.

Some project under my responsability:

- Chilean postal authority Postal Code implementation.
- Design of huge Oracle 8i database instalations.

Inter Media S.A.
Web Developer
August 2000 - May 2001 (10 months)

Design and development of dynamic web systems/applications.

Administration of Linux/Windows NT servers with HTTP (Apache/IIS) and database (MS-SQL/MySQL) services.

Some projects under my responsability:

- Lan Chile website (http://www.lanchile.com)
- BDF Eucerin LatAm (http://www.eucerin-la.com)
- Radio DUNA (http://www.duna.cl)
- Watt's (http://www.watts.cl)

Education

Reuven Lerner

Advanced Python II · (2016 - 2016)

John Bryce

Advanced Python I · (2015 - 2015)

InterBit

Agile TDD with PHP · (2010 - 2010)

VUE Pearson

Zend Certified Engineer PHP 5, Web technologies · (2006 - 2006)

VUE Pearson

Zend Certified Engineer PHP 4, Web technologies · (2005 - 2005)